<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>live-streaming on Maurício Antunes</title>
    <link>https://www.maugzoide.com/tags/live-streaming/</link>
    <description>Recent content in live-streaming on Maurício Antunes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.maugzoide.com/tags/live-streaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a live streaming platform, part II</title>
      <link>https://www.maugzoide.com/posts/building-a-live-streaming-platform-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.maugzoide.com/posts/building-a-live-streaming-platform-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>Building a live streaming platform, part I Building a live streaming platform, part II  This post is the second in the Building a live streaming platform series.
We well cover more information about NGINX-RTMP, adding a way to authorize specific people to stream in our platform.
Youtube, Facebook and Twitch use a stream key to match your identity. Are you itself streaming this new video game?
Authorizing streamings From the point of view of a server, you are a publisher if you configured your software to stream your content, be it recorded (previously recorded media on live channels) or live (your notebook or smartphone camera).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a live streaming platform, part I</title>
      <link>https://www.maugzoide.com/posts/building-a-live-streaming-platform-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.maugzoide.com/posts/building-a-live-streaming-platform-part-i/</guid>
      <description>Building a live streaming platform, part I Building a live streaming platform, part II  Have you ever got yourself thinking how live streaming works?
This post is a guide to build your own live streaming platform. After reading and following the examples included on this post, you will be able to publish your content live.
How live streaming works If you consume videos on Youtube, you probably already had contact with a live video transmited over the web.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>